He's not here to save the world
Brightburn is a horror, science fiction film directed by David Yarovesky.
What if a child from another world crash-landed on Earth, but instead of becoming
a hero to mankind, he proved to be something far more sinister?
Brandon Breyer, played by Jackson A. Dunn.
Tori Breyer, played by Elizabeth Banks.
Kyle Breyer, played by David Denman.
Noah McNichol, played by Matt Jones.
Merilee McNichol, played by Meredith Hagner.
Erica, played by Becky Wahlstrom.
Brightburn is a 2019 American superhero horror film directed by David Yarovesky, written by Brian and Mark Gunn,
and produced by James Gunn and Kenneth Huang, starring Elizabeth Banks, David Denman, Jackson A.
Dunn, Matt Jones, and Meredith Hagner.
The plot follows Brandon Breyer, a young boy of extraterrestrial origin reared on
Earth who discovers he has superpowers, using them with dark intentions.
The film was financed by The H Collective, who
produced with Troll Court Entertainment.
Brightburn was announced as "Untitled James Gunn
Horror Project" in December 2017.
Gunn produced the film, while his brother Brian and cousin Mark penned the
screenplay, which adapts the concept of Superman for explicit horror.
Principal photography began in March 2018 and wrapped in May of that same year.
Brightburn was released in the United States on May 24,
2019, by Screen Gems and Stage 6 Films.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised its visual effects, acting performances,
cinematography, humor, and score, but felt that it did not deliver on the full potential of its premise.
The film grossed $33.2 million against a production budget of
$6–12 million and has gained a cult following.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship,
countryside, child murder, country life, kansas, usa.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.